Deepak Gupta

Gurgaon • 122001

mobile: 9811994713 • email: deepak.gupta4@outlook.com

Profile Summary

Java Developer with 6.11 years of experience in Core Java, Spring, Spring Boot, Microservices across telecom, mobile banking, and aviation domains. Looking for a challenging position as a developer where I will be a valuable member, contributing quality ideas, willing to embrace new challenges which would utilize my technical and analytical skills.

Achievements

Recognition Award: Design Batch File Splitter.

- Client Appreciation: Design and development of auto deployment tool of component for production.
- Responsible for technical client interaction and UAT sign off.

Skills

Backend : Java, Spring MVC, Spring Core, Spring Boot, Hibernate, REST, Struts2,

Netflix Hystrix, Apache Camel, Microservices.

Frontend : HTML, CSS, JSP
OS : Windows, Linux
Server : Jetty, Apache Tomcat

Cache : Hazel Cast, Hazel DB Persistence.

Messaging : Rabbit MQ
Database : Oracle, MySQL

IDE/Tools : Eclipse, STS, Toad, SVN, Putty

Version Control : Maven, Jenkins, GIT

Education

Educational Qualifications	Year	Board/Institution	CGPA*/%
B.Tech, Information Technology	2011	T.I.T & S Bhiwani	76.1
12th Standard	2007	K.V. Air Force Sirsa	85.6
10th Standard	2005	K.V. Air Force Sirsa	75.6

Experience

Nagarro Software Gurgaon (Jan 2016 – Present)

Technology: Java8, Spring, Spring Boot, GIT, MySQL, Maven, REST, CQRS, DDD, Apache Camel, Microservices.

Role: Design, Development, Team Handling, Client Interaction.

Roles and Responsibilities:

- Working closely with clients and business analyst to understand and develop average and high complexity telecom products.
- Develop solutions to integrate and enable communication between various components
- Doing proof of concept for new feature in the product.
- Using new technologies to achieve the functionality.
- Working on agile development manner.
- Develop solution using Junit TDD approach and extensive mocking.
- Exceptional Handling and Security Framework of the Application

• CORS origin support of the application across different domains.

Weather Solution

Description : This Web API exposes an application interface using google protobuf over HTTp. This interface is intended for use by Airline Clients as well as Flight Navigation Systems that need to access the weather features. The main objective is to expose the REST API operations for user agents to interact. Some features that I integrated/developed into the product was OAuth like feature development and writing its validator for the various features, integration with Map Store functionality of Hazel cast etc.

Technology : Actuator, Netflix Hystrix, UNIX, MySQL, Apache Tomcat, Spring, Web Services (REST),

Camel, Junit Testing.

Project Role: Design, Development, Team Handling, Client Interaction.

Web Conferencing Software Solution

Description : This Web API exposes an application interface using XML messaging over HTTP. The interface is intended for use by UI clients as well as by other widgets and internal systems that need to access features. The main objective is to expose the REST API operations for user agents to interact. This project follows TDD approach for the development. Some features that I integrated into the product was OAuth2 Validator Implementation, Versioning for REST API etc.

Technology : AXON Framework(CQRS), REST Docs, Actuator, Netflix Hystrix, UNIX, MySQL, Shell

Scripting, Apache Tomcat, Spring, Web Services, Rabbit MQ, Junit Testing.

Project Role: Design, Development, Team Handling, Client Interaction.

Amdocs DVCI Gurgaon (Aug 2013 – Jan 2016)

Technology: JAVA, JDBC, JSP, Struts, Spring IOC, Apache Tomcat, Maven, Jenkins, Eclipse, Agile

Role: Design, Development, Team Handling, Client Interaction.

Roles and Responsibilities:

- Working closely with clients and business analyst to understand and develop average and high complexity telecom products.
- Develop solutions to integrate and enable communication between various billing products
- Follow SDLC process to design and code the product
- Perform and design unit test using Junit
- Working on agile development manner.

Customer Relationship Management Product (Onsite)

Description : This project is a model for managing a telecom's interactions with current and future customers. It involves using technology to organize, automate, and synchronize sales, marketing, customer service, and technical support. This helps the telecom to increase its revenue. We work on agile software development manner. In this product, I worked on the part of integration with third parties with the help of technologies such as Web Services, Spring, JMS, XML.

Technology : Java, UNIX, Oracle, Shell Scripting, Struts, spring, Web Services.

Project Role: Design, Development, Team Handling, PO Interaction.

Mahindra Comviva, Gurgaon (Aug 2011 – Aug 2013)

Technology: JAVA, Hibernate, Servlets, JSP, Struts, Spring, Apache Tomcat, Eclipse, JUnit

Role : Design, Development, Testing

Roles and Responsibilities:

- Design and develop Mobile-based solutions to provide value added services (VAS) to consumers.
- Follow SDLC process to design and code the product
- Perform and design unit test

Missed Call Alert

Description : Application to integrate an operator's network to capture and manage all missed call attempts of a subscriber when the subscriber is not available. Unique functionality offered as a value-added service that allows operators to enhance ARPU. Develop and integrate mode changer functionality for charging gateway.

Technology : Java, UNIX, JSP, Servlet, MySQL **Project Role** : Design, Development and Unit Testing

Call Completion

Description : Application to handle and manage the calls missed due to B party not reachable or is switched off. Provides the caller to leave voice messages for the called number which can be retrieved by the subscriber through an IVR. Generate MIS reporting of the product on a weekly, monthly and yearly basis. Developed a user interface that was developed to handle the CSR tasks such as provisioning, de-provisioning, bulk subscriptions etc using Spring REST API.

Technology : Java, UNIX, JSP, Servlet, Struts2, spring and Hibernate framework.

Project Role : Design, Development and Unit Testing

Personal Details

Marital Status : Married

Languages : English, Hindi & Punjabi

Passport : Yes

Date of Birth : 01-Feb-1990 Location : Gurgaon